# Ajay Naidu Jami

Sr. System Engineer

Solutions Architect - Associate

j.ajaynaidu@gmail.com | +91-9700053139

GitHub: https://github.com/ajaynaidujami

## Summary

AWS certified Solutions Architect - Associate with 5 years of experience as DevOps Engineer in exposure to Software Configuration Management, Build and Release Management, Continuous Integration, Deployment including 10 months of experience as System Administrator.

# **Key Skills**

AWS	GitHub/GitLab	Docker	Bash	Nexus
Azure/DevOps	Python (Boto3)	Datadog	Ansible	VMWare
Terraform	Windows/Linux	Jenkins	Tomcat	SonarQube
Kubernetes	JFrog Artifactory	ELK Stack	PowerShell	ServiceNow

# **Professional Experience**

TechVedika Pvt. Ltd., Hyderabad from Aug 2019 to till date

## Senior Systems Engineer / DevOps Engineer

- Reduced infra deployment time for critical agile project infrastructure using Terraform.
- Good understanding of Infrastructure as Code, IaC and integration.
- Built infra for large-scale web applications with high availability and response time.
- Extensively worked on **Jenkins** for continuous integration and for End to End automation for all build and deployments. Migrated server hosted Jenkins to **Kubernetes**
- Implemented **ELK Stack** to a java appliance framework for real time log aggregation, analysis and querying (Elasticsearch, Logstash).
- Strong working knowledge on AWS cloud environment in network topologies, infra hardening using IAM and Security groups, EKS, EFS, RDS, KMS, SSM, Elastic Cache.
- Created a zero downtime infra by implementing multi region strategy and load balancing.
- Providing of infra solutions and guiding developers in choosing AWS/Azure services,
  Integration of services with application to monitor, log and analyse the application statics.
- Managed server and network monitoring solutions such as CloudWatch in AWS and enabled notifications using SNS to minimize downtime, Implemented Grafana in local environment.
- Developed **PowerShell** scripts for achieving automation and for various projects to sync realtime data from remote to application env with minimum latency.
- Migrated production running applications to Kubernetes infra in both Azure and AWS
- Have streamlined DevOps methodology in **Azure DevOps** for azure cloud-based projects
- Built daily backup solution for DBs' in Azure Cosmos to Azure Blob Containers
- Worked with developers to ensure new environments both met their requirements and conformed to industry-standard best practices.
- Currently introducing more open source solutions to the organization.

## **DXC.Technology**, Hyderabad from SEP 2015 to Aug 2019

### **Associate Professional System Administrator**

- Building infrastructure in AWS environment with help of Terraform and Packer.
- Developed and maintained automated CI/CD pipelines for code deployment using **Jenkins**.
- Build jobs, Plugins installation and management, setting up Master/slaves in Jenkins.
- AWS service administration: IAM, VPC, Route53, EC2, CloudWatch, S3, Elasticsearch.
- Installed and configured centralised logging with **ELK** (Elasticsearch Logstash Kibana) to constantly analyse system and application logs and events.
- Managed **GitLab** repositories and permissions, including branching and tagging.
- Managed 30+ servers in a distributed and highly available critical infrastructure.
- **Ubuntu** and **Windows** system administration and performance tuning.
- Installation, Configuration and Management of web/application servers such as **Tomcat.**
- Experience in Domain creation and management of various public/private websites in **Route53.**
- Designed and implementing a **DR** and **HA** in AWS infra using autoscaling and backup policies.
- Had working experience with concepts such as setup, Inventory, Playbooks, Roles, Tasks and Modules in Ansible.
- Experience in working with Docker for creation of Docker Images and Containers.
- Building **Kubernetes** cluster set-up and deploying of **Kubernetes** setup on using kops.
- Tracking of all build related bugs using ticketing/bug tracking tool ServiceNow.
- Server administration and multi-platform support (OS X, Ubuntu, Windows).
- Provide direct server support during deployment and general production operations.
- Troubleshooting of deployment issues in the Dev., QA and Pre-Prod environments.
- Implemented cost savings techniques using **Terraform** and **Jenkins** to scaleup and destroy infra when required.
- Daily user support for enterprise systems, networking and workstations.
- As part of best practises, created and updated the documentation of newly setup software/infra steps.
- Automated deployment of web applications in servers using Jenkins plugins and wrote backup shell scripts for major application and configuration data.

# **Project Summary**

# **Fleeting Pro**

Duration: Feb 2020 to Till date

Team Size: 7

Role Played: DevOps and Azure Cloud Engineer

Skills Used: Azure, AzureDevOps, CosmosDB, ELK Cloud, Apache, Docker and Kubernetes

## Arevea.com/.tv

Duration: Dec 2019 to Till date

Team Size: 20

Role Played: DevOps and AWS Architect/Cloud Engineer

Skills Used: AWS, DigitalOcean, Ubuntu, Apache, Jenkins, Domain management

#### **Prospercare**

Duration: Mar 2020 to Till date

Team Size: 7

Role Played: DevOps and Azure Cloud Engineer

Skills Used: Azure, CosmosDB, ELK Cloud, Ubuntu, Shell, Apache, Jenkins, Groovy

#### **HBL TCAS**

Duration: Sep 2019 to Mar 2020

Team Size: 6

Role Played: DevOps Engineer and System Administrator

Skills Used: ELK Stack, Windows Server 2012, Jenkins, PowerShell, IIS, Samba

#### Manulife

Duration: Sep 2015 to Aug 2019

Team Size: 9

Role Played: System Administrator and AWS Architect

Skills Used: AWS, Server Management, Apache, Ubuntu, Shell, Terraform and Kubernetes

#### Education

Electrical and Electronic Engineering (Degree) (2015 – 2019)

Lenora College of Engineering, Rampachodavaram

Electrical and Electronic Engineering (Diploma) (2012 – 2015)

Aditya Polytechnic College, Surampalem

Secondary School Certificate (SSC) (2012)

Nivedita Kishore Vihar E.M, Rajahmundry

## Personal Profile

Date of Birth : 21st Oct 1996 Marital Status : Unmarried

Current Location: Hyderabad, Telangana

# Languages Known

English Hindi Telugu

#### Declaration

I hereby solemnly affirm that all the information furnished by me is true to the best of my knowledge.

Date: Aug 27, 2020 (Ajay Naidu Jami)